Let's build on top of our knowledge about feature extraction and object recognition,
既然学习了特征提取和物体识别
and think about how we might be able to simplify and speed up this whole pipeline.
我们来思考要怎么简化并加速整个流水线
In this example, we'll be building
以建立人脸检测器为例
a face detector working with an algorithm called Haar cascades.
这个检测器的建立涉及到一个叫 Haar 级联的算法
This algorithm works by training on many positive images
要使用该算法 我们需要训练算法学习许多正例图像 (有人脸的图像)
(images of faces) and negative images (images without faces).
和负例图像 (无人脸的图像)
First, from each image,
首先 算法会从每个图像中
it detects so-called Haar features.
检测出所谓的 Haar 特征
Haar features are gradient measurements that look at rectangular regions around
Haar 特征就是梯度测量值 测量时 算法会观察某个特定像素区域周围的矩形区域
a certain pixel area and somewhat subtract these areas to calculate a pixel difference.
以某种方式减去这些区域 从而计算像素差
This is similar to how convolution kernels work,
这与卷积核的工作原理有些类似
only at a larger scale.
但是规模更大
Haar features detect patterns like edges,
Haar 特征能检测边缘、
lines, and more complex rectangular patterns.
线条和更复杂的矩形等模式
In the case of face detection,
在人脸检测中
lines and rectangles are especially useful features because patterns
线条和矩形是特别实用的特征
of alternating bright and dark areas define a lot of features on a face.
因为明暗交替的区域块能确定许多脸部特征
For example, our pupils are typically a very dark feature,
比如 我们的瞳孔通常都是种很黑的特征
and cheeks and chins define a high gradient outline for a face.
脸颊和下巴则确定了脸部的高梯度轮廓
So far, Haar features are looking pretty similar
到目前为止 Haar 特征的步骤看起来很像
to the beginning steps of a convolutional neural network,
卷积神经网络的前几步
or even HOG feature extraction,
甚至像 HOG 特征提取的前几步
but the next step is different,
但下一步就不同了
it's a series of cascades.
接着是一系列的级联
For any image of a face,
任意人脸图像
a large portion of this image will be a non-face region.
有很大一部分都非人脸区域
So what a Haar cascade does is,
所以 Haar 级联
it looks at an image and applies
会观察图像
a Haar feature detector like this vertical line detector,
对图像应用 Haar 特征检测器 比如这个垂直线检测器
and then performs classification on the entire image.
然后对整张图像进行分类处理
If it doesn't get enough of a feature detection response,
如果特征检测器回应不够
it classifies an area of an image as "not face" and discards this information.
那 Haar 级联就会将图像的一部分区域归为 “非人脸” 并舍弃这部分信息
Then, it feeds this reduced image area to
然后将经过删减的图像
the next feature detector and classifies the image again,
放到下一个特征检测器中 再次进行图像分类
discarding irrelevant non-face areas at every step.
每次都会舍弃一部分无关的非人脸区域
This is called a "cascade of classifiers."
我们称这个过程为 “分类器的级联”
In this way, Haar cascades focus on processing
通过这种方法 Haar 级联能重点处理
and recognizing only the area in an image that's been
并识别图像的特定部分
classified as part of a face already and quickly throwing
也即已归为人脸的部分
out irrelevant image data makes this algorithm very fast,
这种迅速舍弃图像无关数据的举措使得这个算法运算十分迅速
fast enough for processing a video stream in real time on a laptop computer.
因而能在笔记本电脑里实时处理视频流
Haar cascades may also be used in selecting an area of
我们还可以用 Haar 级联选出特定区域来进行后续处理
interest for further processing so let's get more practice with Haar cascades. 最新课程跟课件还有一对一辅导请加wx：udacity6
让我们多做几个 Haar 级联的练习吧